NWOHIRI MICHAEL

PROFILE

To build a career in an organization where I can gain experience and get the opportunity to prove my ability by accepting challenges, fulfilling the organizational goals and climb the career ladder through continuous learning and commitment, by being dynamic and converting insurmountable tasks into challenges, ensuring that they are accomplished in accordance.

www.devdera.netlify.app/

ACTIVITIES AND INTERESTS

- Research
- Web development
- Sports
- Travel
- Great food
- Food Pantry Volunteer

KEY SKILLS

- Sales management
- Research
- **Analytics**
- Html, CSS, JavaScript
- Attention to details
- Excellent listener
- Friendly, courteous, & service oriented
- Composed under pressure
- Quality assurance
- Solid written & verbal communicator

WORK EXPERIENCE

Microbiology Intern

Federal Ministry of Water Resources | Lagos, Nigeria April 2021 - August 2021

Produced high-quality communications for Internal and external use. • Reported back to instructor to receive day-to-day tasks and responsibilities. • Sorted, organized and maintained files. • Searched at library and in scholarly databases to locate necessary information for research projects • Communicated effectively with faculty and staff and accepted critiques and suggestions for areas of improvement. Completed research, compiled data and assisted in timely reporting. • prepared culture media for isolation and growth of microbes for examination. • prepared biochemical medium such as indole test for isolation of E. coli. • conducted antimicrobial susceptibility test on cultured E. coli strains

Sales Representative

BENNWO Associates Limited, International trade fair center | Lagos, Nigeria 2022 - 2023

• Connecting with professionals in the center to foster business relationships • Administrative support in services such as typing, documentation and secretarial assistance • Managed smallscale projects • Sorted and stored files • Communicating effectively with other staffs •shadowing sales technicians and experts •Generating invoice for sales

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Microbiology

Landmark University, Kwara, Nigeria September 2018 – August 2022

Master of Sciences in Advanced Biomedical Science

De Montfort University, Leicester, United Kingdom February 2024 – Date

Mandatory Care training with practical

Victory training academy, Leicester, United Kingdom March 2024